Register of the Joseph Freeman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1915-1964
  Clippings, pamphlets, printed articles, leaflets, programs, speeches, newsletters, notes, serial issues, reports, correspondence, lists, memoranda, bulletins, book reviews, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General
    - General. Clippings, notes, newsletters, flyers, unidentified typescript, memorandum, and miscellany, 1933-1964 (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - Biographical information. List, printed matter, resumes, and eulogies, 1924-1964 (Folder 2)
    - Book reviews and bibliographies. Lists and printed matter, 1939-1963 (Folder 3)
  - Agriculture. Flyers, reports (by Freeman and others?), program, correspondence and printed material, 1931-1939 (Folder 4)
    Includes material relating to the organization of a milk producers cooperative in New York State
  - American Artists Congress. Minutes, conference material, printed matter, list, correspondence with Heywood Broun, Rockwell Kent and others, report, notes, statements and writings by Jose Clemente Orozco, Freeman and others, 1935-1937 (Folder 5)
  - American Artists School. Printed matter, correspondence, and writing by Freeman, 1936-1937 (Folder 6)
  - American Association of Proletarian Writers. Circulars and correspondence with M. Mendelevsky, Charles Ruthenberg and another, 1925-1926 (Folder 7)
  - American Civil Liberties Union
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1931-1956 (Folder 8-9)
      - Non-printed matter. Memoranda, notes, reports, and miscellany, 1943-1953 (Box 165, Folder 1)
      - Printed matter. Pamphlets, newsletters, flyers, and clippings, 1934-1964 (Folder 2-4)
    - Public Relations Committee. Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and press releases, 1948-1955 (Folder 5-6)
  - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO).
    Includes material relating to the unity convention of 1955
    - Non-printed matter. Circular, report, miscellany, speeches and statements by Dwight David Eisenhower, Walter Reuther, Adlai Stevenson, and Robert Wagner, 1945-1955 (Folder 7)
    - Printed matter. Flyers, pamphlets, convention proceedings, report, and clippings
      - Undated (Folder 8)
      - 1940-1955 (Box 166, Folder 1-3)
  - American Jewish Committee. Pamphlets, 1948-1951 (Folder 4)
  - American League for Peace and Democracy. Program, minutes, and correspondence with William Browder and others, 1932-1940. (Folder 5)
    Includes American Committee for the World Congress Against War, the American Committee Against Fascist Oppression in Germany, the American League Against War and Fascism, and other related organizations. SEE ALSO: Barbusse, Henri
  - Anarchism and syndicalism. Printed articles, 1930-1963 (Folder 6)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith. Bulletins, flyers, letters, press releases, report, notes, and miscellany, 1944-1947 (Folder 7)
  - Anti-Imperialist League of the United States. Newsletter, flyer, and correspondence with Conrad Komorowski, 1933-1934 (Folder 8)
  - Art. Printed matter, flyers, catalogs, and correspondence (Folder 9)
    - 1931-1945
    - 1946-1964 (Box 167, Folder 1)
  - Authors League of America. Correspondence and miscellany, 1938-1946 (Folder 2)
  - Ballet. Program and holograph production scenario, undated (Folder 3)
  - Barbusse, Henri. Clippings, flyer, miscellany, correspondence with H. W. L. Dana, Robert Morss Lovett, Joseph Pass and others, speeches by Dana and Barbusse (translated and edited by Freeman?), 1933-1936 (Folder 4)
  - Beck, George. Mimeograph copy of "Take a Letter, Darling," (fiction writing), undated (Folder 5)
  - Bennett, Orson. Typescript copy of "The Philistine and the Fool," (fiction writing), undated (Folder 6)
  - Bodenheim, Max. Clippings, 1954 (Folder 7)
  - Bonaparte, Jerome. Extensive notes by Freeman, undated (Folder 8)
  - Bonaparte, Napoleon. Printed article and correspondence, 1955-1956 (Folder 9)
  - Boys High School. Correspondence, printed material, and report, 1944-1955 (Folder 10)
  - Browder, Earl. Clippings and writings by Browder, 1927-1963 (Box 168, Folder 1-4)
    Including typescript copies of "Is Planning Possible Under Capitalism?" (with George Soule), "Relations Between the American Communist Party and the Communist International," "Some Notes on the Revaluation of Stalin," "Memo on the Communist Impact on American Literature," "Marxism and America," "Socialism in the Sixties," "On the Sino-Soviet Conflict," and mimeograph copies of "In Defense of Communism Against W. Z. Foster's 'New Route to Socialism,'" "Keynes, Foster and Marx" (2 vols.), "The Meaning of MacArthur," "Should America Be Returned to the Indians?" and "Karl Marx and America,"
  - Burnham, James. Transcribed article and typescript copy of a letter to the editor by Burnham, 1947 (Folder 5)
  - Calverton, V. F. Printed articles by Calverton and others, 1927-1933 (Folder 6)
  - Chambers, Whittaker. Interview, writings by Chambers, and clippings, 1950-1961 (Folder 7)
    SEE ALSO: Hiss, Alger
  - China. Correspondence, printed matter, and pamphlet, 1934-1961 (Folder 8)
  - Civil liberties. Press release, letter, report, legal documents, and printed matter, 1918-1957 (Folder 9)
    SEE ALSO: American Civil Liberties Union
  - Civil rights. Speech, letter, and printed matter, 1932-1958 (Folder 10)
  - Clark, Judith. Typescript copy of "The Road," (fiction), 1963 (Folder 11)
  - Columbia University. Correspondence, newsletters, printed matter, and writing by Freeman?, 1944-1964 (Box 169, Folder 1)
  - Communism. Pamphlet, clippings, and mimeograph report, 1926-1959 (Folder 2)
  - Communism--United States.
    SEE ALSO: Espionage
    - Non-printed matter. Notes, reports, miscellany, printed issuances and correspondence with members of the Communist Party, U.S.A. and others, 1926-1956 (Folder 3)
    - Printed matter. Newsletters, clippings, pamphlets, convention bulletin, and flyer, 1928-1958 (Folder 4-7)
  - Communism in education. Meeting memoranda, government reports, and printed matter, 1940-1953 (Folder 8)
  - Communism in literature and art. Correspondence, prospectus, typescript report entitled "Problems of the Cultural Front," printed matter, pamphlets by Mike Gold and others, 1933-1964 (Folder 9)
    SEE ALSO: John Reed Clubs
  - Communist International (Comintern). Convention material, pamphlet, minutes, and printed matter, 1921-1963 (Box 170, Folder 1)
  - Coplon, Judith. Clippings, 1949 (Folder 2)
  - Cuba. Broadcast transcript, flyers, notes, printed matter, and typescript reports, including Juan Bosch, "Batista Wins Again,", 1944-1961 (Folder 3)
  - Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace. Form letters, 1949 (Folder 4)
  - Dell, Floyd. Correspondence with S. Thomas Tanselle, 1959 (Folder 5)
  - Dissenters (organization). Correspondence and announcements, 1941-1964 (Folder 6)
  - Dos Passos, John. Correspondence and printed writings by Dos Passos, Michael Gold and others, 1933-1963 (Folder 7)
  - Eastman, Max. Printed matter, including writings by Eastman, Joshua Kunitz, Romain Rolland and others, and typescript writings by Eastman, including "A Reply to My Official Critics," and a letter to the editor of Nation, 1918-1956 (Folder 8)
  - Economics. Pamphlets, flyers, speech, reports, newsletter, and typescript copies of Harry Jerome, "Measurement of Productivity Changes and the Displacement of Labor," Lewis L. Lorwin, "Some Political Aspects of Economic Planning," Walter E. Spahr, "Bank Failures in the United States,", 1931-1957 (Folder 9)
  - Eichmann, Adolf. Clippings, 1960-1961 (Folder 10)
  - Eisler, Hanns. Flyer and clipping, 1947-1948 (Folder 11)
  - Erskine, Dorothy. Proof copy of The Crystal Boat (fiction), 1946 (Folder 12)
  - Espionage. Clippings and printed transcripts and reports, 1939-1957 (Folder 13)
  - Fascism. Printed matter and typescript writings, including a letter to the editor by Lawrence Dennis, 1916-1949 (Box 171, Folder 1)
  - Fast, Howard. Clippings, 1957-1958 (Folder 2)
  - Faulkner, William. Clippings, 1951-1961 (Folder 3)
  - Film and photography. Correspondence, report, newsletter, printed matter, and flyers, 1931-1963 (Folder 4)
    Includes material relating to the Film and Photo League
  - Fourth International. Election material, printed matter, and flyers, Primarily relates to the Socialist Workers Party, 1940-1962 (Folder 5)
  - Friends of the Soviet Union. Correspondence and flyer, 1933-1936 (Folder 6)
  - Fund for the Republic. Report and clipping, 1953-1955 (Folder 7)
  - Germany. Pamphlets (in German), flyer, correspondence, unidentified typescript writings, mimeograph copy of "A New Start: Fascism or Socialism," and Karl Von Wiegand, "Report on the Blood Purge of June 30, 1934,", 1932-1962 (Folder 8-9)
  - Hemingway, Ernest. Clippings, and cover letters with a biographical typescript by Bill Smith, 1941-1961 (Folder 10)
  - Hervey, Harry. Mimeograph copy of "Shanghai Express," (movie scenario?), undated (Folder 11)
  - Hiss, Alger. Clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - History. Printed matter and miscellany, 1951-1964 (Folder 2)
  - India. Newsletters, correspondence, printed matter, and miscellany, 1930-1962 (Folder 3)
    Includes material relating to the India League of America
  - Institute of Pacific Relations. Letters and printed hearing transcript, 1933-1952 (Folder 4)
  - International Bureau of Revolutionary Literature. Correspondence with Sergei Dinamov and others, program statements, bulletins, resolutions, and notes, 1930-1934 (Folder 5-6)
    Includes material relating to the Kharkov Conference (1930 November)
  - Jews and Jewish organizations. Correspondence, notes, and printed matter, 1933-1964 (Folder 7)
  - John Reed Clubs. Memoranda, reports (by Freeman and others?), minutes, circulars, conference material, bulletins, printed matter, and correspondence with Alan Calmer, Oakley Johnson, Bernhard J. Stern and others, 1932-1935 (Folder 8)
  - Journalism. Lists, letter, clippings, and a proposal for a children's newspaper, circa 1933-1961 (Box 173, Folder 1)
  - Kempton, Murray. Writings by Kempton, 1955 (Folder 2)
  - Korea. Pamphlet and flyers, 1952 (Folder 3)
  - Labor. Letters, printed matter, flyers, conference material, and a mimeograph copy of Al Nash, "Some Views on the Trade Union Movement Today,", 1925-1959 (Folder 4)
    SEE ALSO: AFL-CIO
  - Lamont, Corliss. Circular, writings by Lamont, and printed matter, 1953-1962 (Folder 5)
  - Latin America. Flyer, notes by Freeman, and printed matter, including a pamphlet by Romulo Betancourt, 1937-1955 (Folder 6)
  - League of American Writers. Reports, conference material, agenda, minutes, memoranda, speeches and statements (by Freeman and others?), notes, flyers, lists, printed matter, and correspondence with Alan Calmer, Franklin Folsom, Louis Gibarti, Henry Hart, David Ogden Stewart, Ernst Toller and others, 1935-1941 (Folder 7-10)
  - League of Professional Groups [for Foster and Ford]. Correspondence, memorandum, notes, and printed matter, 1932-1933 (Folder 11)
  - Lerner, Max. Writings, 1948-1961 (Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Liga de Escritores y Artistas Revolucionarios (LEAR). Conference material, typescript speeches by Waldo Frank, Joe Jones, and Juan Marinello, printed matter, a typescript copy of Charmion von Wiegand, "Report on the LEAR Congress," and correspondence with Julio de la Fuente, Enrique Gonzalez Aparicio, Juan Marinello and others, 1934-1937 (Folder 2)
  - Literature. Letter, clippings, and writings, including a typescript copy of Eugene Lyons, "Popular American Periodical Literature,", 1930-1963 (Folder 3-4)
  - Litvinov, Ivy and Maksim. Clippings, notes, miscellany, letter, drawings by Ivy Litvinov and another, writings by Ivy Litvinov, and extensive notes by Freeman, 1933-1961 (Folder 5-7)
  - McCarthy, Joseph. Clippings, newsletters, and circular, 1953-1954 (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - Mailer, Norman. Clippings, 1962 (Folder 2)
  - Mancisidor, Jose. Typescript copy of "De una madre espanola,", 1937 (Folder 3)
  - Mann, Thomas. Program, clipping, pamphlet, and correspondence with Freda Kirchwey and Robert Sherwood, 1940-1945 (Folder 4)
  - Marcantonio, Vito. Clippings, statement by Marcantonio, and election material, 1950-1954 (Folder 5)
  - Melville, Herman. Proof copy of Jay Leyda, The Melville Log, 1951 (Folder 6)
  - Mexico. Pamphlets, printed matter, memorandum, questionnaire, notes, typescript writings by others, including M. Diaz Ramirez, "La Tayectoria economica de una comunidad agraria y el nuevo metodo de explotacion colectiva ejidal en la laguna," and correspondence with Alex Carrillo, Heinrich (Enrique) Gutmann, Hernan Laborde and others, 1927-1955 (Folder 7-9)
  - Mexico (Box 176, Folder 1-4)
  - Mixas, Adolfas. Typescript copy of Hallelujah the Hills, (film script), press release, printed matter, and letter by Mixas, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Modotti, Tina. Pamphlet (in Spanish), 1942 (Folder 6)
  - Music. Letter and programs, 1934-1962 (Folder 7)
  - New Leader, Form letters, list, and typescript public relations material developed by Freeman?, 1950-1958 (Folder 8)
  - New Masses
    - General
      - Non-printed matter. Memoranda, minutes, reports, lists, a poem by Al Taylor, and miscellany (Folder 9)
        - Undated
        - 1925-1939 (Box 177, Folder 1)
      - Printed matter. Flyers, circulars, and printed articles, 1936-1948 (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General, Includes correspondence with John Alroy, Michael Blankfort, Haakon Chevalier, Margaret DeSilver, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Michael Gold, Granville Hicks, Oakley Johnson, Freda Kirchwey, Conrad Komorowski, Joshua Kunitz, Abe Magil, Herman Michelson, Scott Nearing, Ezra Pound, Edwin Rolfe, Sam Sillen, Bernard Smith, Fay Spiro, Ruth Stout, Al Taylor and others. Also includes letter of resignation by Max Eastman and Louis Lozowick, 1925-1940 (Folder 3-11)
      - Black, Helen, 1925?-1929 (Folder 12)
      - Browder, Bill, 1933-1935 (Folder 13)
      - Carmon, Walter, 1929-1931 (Folder 14)
      - Harrison, Charles Yale, 1931-1938 (Folder 15)
        Includes report, printed articles, and statement by the New Masses editors relating to Harrison's resignation
      - Magil, Abe, 1931-1937 (Folder 16)
      - North, Joe, 1933?-1939 (Folder 17)
      - Schneider, Isidor, 1934-1936 (Folder 18)
      - Willner, George and Tiba [Garlin], 1935-1938 (Folder 19)
  - Nomad, Max. Writings collected for a book?, undated (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - Nuclear energy and weapons. Printed matter and miscellany, 1951-1960 (Folder 2)
  - O'Dwyer, William. Biographical sketches, memorandum, letter, election material, and clippings, 1940-1962 (Folder 3)
  - P.E.N. Correspondence and miscellany, 1943-1951 (Folder 4)
  - Pasternak, Boris. Letter, broadcast transcript, and printed matter, including an article by Pasternak, 1957-1961 (Folder 5)
  - Philosophy. Miscellany, printed articles by James Feibleman and others, and typescript writings by I. Rice Pereira, and another, 1924-1964 (Folder 6-8)
  - Pilynak, Boris. Clippings, notes, miscellany, and correspondence with Louis Fischer, Michael Korovay, Isaac Don Levine, Al Lewin, Lester Markel, Albert Parry, Ruth Raphael, Upton Sinclair and others, 1931-1933 (Folder 9)
  - Poetry
    - General. Letters, clipings, and a mimeograph copy of Gregor Sebba, "Apple or Mirror: Truth in Poetry,", 1933-1964 (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - Writings by others
      - General, 1920-1964 (Folder 2-3)
        Includes a holograph writing by Gregory Corso
      - Hulbeck, Charles R. (Richard Huelsenbeck). Poems, pamphlet, and biographical sketch, 1950 (Folder 4)
      - Williams, Oscar. Miscellany and poems, 1940-1955 (Folder 5)
  - Poyntz, Juliet Stuart. Clipping and holograph report, 1949 (Folder 6)
  - Psychology and psychoanalysis. Letters, notes, and printed matter, 1944-1953 (Folder 7)
  - Refugees and exiles. Correspondence, typescript copy of "Die 'Winnipeg' Trift vergessene Juden auf Trinidad," flyers, miscellany, and Russian emigre serial issues, 1933-1951 (Folder 8-9)
    SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE FILE/Selva, Solomon de la
  - Refregier, Anton. Press release, correspondence with Refregier, and printed matter, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - Religion. Printed matter, miscellany, and typescript copy of N. J. Waldorf, "Armageddon,", 1941-1962 (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - Ribbentrop, Joachim. Galley proofs of Paul Schwarz, This Man Ribbentrop: His Life and Times, undated (Folder 2)
  - Rivera, Diego. Printed matter, writings by Rivera, David Alfaro Siquieros, Bertram Wolfe and others, extensive notes by Freeman, and correspondence with Louis Bunin, Pablo O'Higgins, Fay Spiro, Paca Toor and others, 1925-1956 (Folder 3-5)
  - Robinson, Ione. Drawings by Ione Robinson, clippings, and notes by Freeman, 1929-1946 (Folder 6-7)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin. Circular, program, pamphlet, and list, 1949 (Folder 8)
  - Rosenberg, Ethel and Julius. Clippings and pamphlet, 1951-1954 (Folder 9)
  - Roumain, Jacques. Correspondence, 1939 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - Science and medicine. Printed matter, pamphlet relating to Albert Schweitzer (in German), notes, and program, 1941-1963 (Folder 2-3)
    Includes material relating to proposed national health insurance
  - Sinclair, Upton. Leaflet, printed writing, and a mimeograph copy of "He Loved the Queen" (unpublished play script?) by Sinclair, and correspondence with Oscar Cargill, 1938-1963 (Folder 4)
  - Socialism. Pamphlets, letters, flyers, printed matter, election material, typescript copy of "Manifesto of the Democratic Socialist Party," mimeograph copies of Jack Cypin, "Capitalism and Socialism: A Problem of Semantics," "Planning and Automation," and "Planning for Freedom," Arthur Field, "The Future of Urban Living Under Democratic Socialism," Erich Fromm, "A Socialist Manifesto and Program" (with notes, drafts, and comments by others), Michael Harrington, "The New Programs of the Austrian, German and British Parties," Francis Heisler, "Nature of the Socialist Society," Warren Morse, "Socialism--1959," Mulford Sibley, "The Attitude of Socialism to Industrialism and Technology" and "The Socialist Attitude to War and Defense," Harry Siitonen, "The Negro on the American Political Scene," Primarily relates to the Socialist Party-Social Democratic Federation, 1945-1964 (Folder 5-6)
  - Soviet Russia Today. Correspondence and printed matter, 1934-1939 (Folder 7)
  - Soviet Union
    - General
      - Non-printed matter. Memorandum, letter, notes, reports, press releases, typescript copies of George S. Counts, "Economic Planning in the Soviet Union," Simon Liberman, "Building Lenin's Russia," and Louis Nizer, "What to Do With Russia,", 1931-1959 (Folder 8)
      - Non-printed matter (Box 182, Folder 1)
      - Printed matter. Clippings, pamphlets, reports, commemorative booklet, and miscellany (Folder 2-6)
        - 1919-1964
    - Film. Printed matter, including an AMKINO brochure, notes (in English and Russian), a typescript copy of Sergei M. Eisenstein, "The General Line," and correspondence with Marie Seton relating to Eisenstein, 1948-1951 (Box 183, Folder 1)
      SEE ALSO: Photographs
    - Literature and art
      - Correspondence, 1927-1957 (Folder 2)
        Includes the U.S.S.R. Society of Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries, Literaturnaya Gazeta, Soviet Information Bureau, Scholarly-Research Institute of Foreign Bibliography, the Union of Soviet Writers and others
      - Non-printed matter. List of authors, typescript copies of A. Lejnev, "Belles-Lettres," Vsevold Meyerhold, "Akter budushchego," "V Uzbekgoskino," and a review of Aleksandr Tairov, Zapiski rezhissera, Alexander Serafimovitch, "Criticism by the Masses" (translated by Freeman?), a commentary on the staging of a play, "Rychi, Kitai!" at the Meyerhold Theatre, "Proletarian Culture," and other unidentified writings, letter, and notes, 1921-1933 (Folder 3)
      - Printed matter. Clippings, speech by N. Khrushchev, program, printed articles, and pamphlets (in Russian) of both literary and artistic works, including a biography of Vsevold Meyerhold, 1921-1963 (Folder 4-7)
    - Moscow Trials. Clippings, letter to the editor, mimeograph copy of "An Outline on Counter-Revolutionary Trotskyism," printed matter relating to the Zinoviev et al. and Radek-Piatokov trials, 1936-1938 (Folder 8)
  - Spain. Pamphlets, correspondence with Milton Felsen and others, speech by Manuel Azana, newsletters (Volunteer for Liberty), clippings, statements prepared for the New Masses by Andre Malraux, Ludwig Renn and another, and a holograph copy of "Lincoln Battalion Laughs,", 1937-1940 (Box 184, Folder 1)
    SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE FILE/Friedman, Jack and Rolfe, Edwin; SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (PROSE) FILE/"Spanish Letters," 1960
  - Speare, Dorothy. Memorial printed matter, 1951 (Folder 2)
  - Steffens, Lincoln. Letter and typescript anecdote, 1961 (Folder 3)
  - Strong, Anna Louise. Newsletters and printed matter, 1949-1953 (Folder 4)
  - TASS. Clippings, notes, and correspondence with Kenneth Durant, Harry Freeman, and Bessie Weissman, 1925-1954 (Folder 5)
  - Theatre and drama
    - General. Programs, clippings, letters, typescript report, "Proposal for a Workers Theatre," a mimeograph copy of Richard Collins and Anne Greene, "See What I Mean," and other unidentified writings by others, 1932-1956 (Folder 6-7)
    - New Theatre League. Program, correspondence with Herb Kline and others, serial issue, and a typescript copy of Michael Blankfort, "Facing the New Audience: Sketches Toward an Aesthetic for the Revolutionary Theatre,", 1933-1937 (Folder 8)
    - Poets' Theatre. Memorandum, letters by Maria Piscator, program, notes, and press release, 1948 (Folder 9)
    - Theatre Guild. Correspondence with Ruth Benedict and another, 1925 (Folder 10)
    - Theatre Union. Clippings, correspondence with Sylvia Fenningston, Margaret Larkin, Paul Peters, Charles Walker and others, memoranda by Manuel Gomez and Liston Oak, typescript copies of "The Theatre Union Presents--A Prospectus for a Workers' Theatre," and "Theatre of the Trade Unions," and a mimeograph draft copy of Bertold Brecht, "Mother,", 1933-1936 (Folder 11)
    - United Nations Theatre. Notes, undated (Folder 12)
    - Workers Laboratory Theatre. Correspondence with Stephen Karnot, 1935 (Folder 13)
  - Toller, Ernst. Letters to Toller and another, clippings, typescript report, and a poem relating to Toller's suicide, 1925-1940 (Folder 14)
  - Tresca, Carlo. Form letter and clippings relating to the death of Tresca, 1943-1949 (Folder 15)
  - Trotsky, Leon. Printed matter, writings by Trotsky, bulletin, letter, and sketch of Trotsky, 1925-1960 (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - U-2 incident. Clippings, 1960 (Folder 2)
  - United Services Organization (U.S.O.). Clippings and mimeograph copy of Carl C. Gray, "The Outskirts of Civilization (and the Underskirts, Too),", 1945 (Folder 3)
  - United States--Politics and government. Election material, printed matter, letters, and mimeograph copy of Stanley Pargellis, "The Tradition of Conservatism in America,", 1933-1961 (Folder 4)
  - Von Wiegand, Charmion. Programs, typescript copies of one-act plays by von Wiegand, and printed articles written by von Wiegand in Moscow, 1926-1941 (Folder 5)
  - Von Wiegand, Karl. Press release, correspondence, clippings, typescript and printed writings by von Wiegand, and will, 1928-1961 (Folder 6)
  - Wallace, Henry A. Clippings, speech, and printed article by Wallace, 1942-1950 (Folder 7)
  - Webb, Beatrice and Sidney. Printed matter and typescript play script (incomplete), circa 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Webb, Beatrice and Sidney (Box 186, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, Edmund. Printed matter, 1940-1943 (Folder 2)
  - Wittfogel, Karl. Printed articles, 1930?-1953 (Folder 3)
  - Women. Clippings, letters, and miscellany, 1949-1963 (Folder 4)
  - Workers education. Correspondence and typescript report, 1923-1933 (Folder 5)
  - Works Progress Administration. Federal Art Project